emailonacid.com 2019-12-13

# Privacy Policy - Email On Acid

Trusted by more than 80,000 businesses worldwide.

Email on Acid has a strong commitment to providing excellent service to our customers, including respecting their concerns about privacy. We understand that visitors to our website may have questions about how this website collects and uses personal information. We have prepared this statement to inform you of the privacy principles that govern [www.emailonacid.com](http://www.stage.e360labs.com/).

This statement contains numerous general and technical details about the steps we take to respect your privacy concerns. The bottom line is that the needs and expectations of our customers form the foundation of everything we do – including protecting your privacy.

This website does contain links to other websites. Please review each website’s individual privacy policies for specific information on how they handle your information. If, after reviewing this Statement you have any privacy questions or concerns, please contact us here.

#####  **Browsing**

While you are browsing our website, we may collect and store information for contacting you in a business environment. This data is limited to your first and last name, email address, LinkedIn profile, and business internet protocol (IP) address. We may also process other business-related data, including job title and function, business name, and business address.

An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer every time you browse the Internet. When users request a page from our site, our servers log the user’s current IP address. We also use IP addresses to help diagnose problems.

#####  **Cookies**

Our website uses “cookie” technology. “Cookies” are encrypted strings of text that a website stores on a user’s computer. Our website requires the use of cookies to:

  * Recognize return visitors;
  * Prevent the same user from making repeated enrollments in our Email on Acid membership program
  * Store and recall user preferences and identify which of our web pages are most useful for our visitors; and
  * Measure usage of our site and the various pages on the site.

The type of cookies that we use are referred to as “persistent” cookies because they remain on a user’s computer hard drive until the user deletes them. We do not use cookies to gather information concerning your visits to other sites, nor ascertain any personal information about you apart from your dealings with [www.emailonacid.com](http://www.stage.e360labs.com/). Cookies do not corrupt or damage your computer or computer files.

Following the rollout of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) on May 25, 2018, users saw language on pages where we enable cookies. We ask users to expressly opt in to our cookie policy to browse our website. If you do not wish to receive these cookies, you may set your browser to reject the cookies (consult the instructions for your browser on how to do this), although doing so may affect your ability to perform certain transactions on our website.

#####  **Information We Collect and How We Use It**

When we need to collect information from you, we will ask you to voluntarily supply us with the information we need. For example, if you would like to sign up as a member on our website, we will ask you for information such as name, address, telephone number, email address, credit card type, credit card number, expiration date in order to process your request. We will use your email address to send a confirmation and, if necessary, might use the other information to contact you for help in processing your membership or specifically for membership maintenance purposes.

We may also ask you to fill out an online customer survey to obtain your suggestions or comments about your use of Email on Acid products or services. Providing this information is voluntary and may be used for direct marketing. We may also send you direct marketing based on information collected when you or a business colleague visits our website, but only when we believe there is a genuine, legitimate interest in our services.

We treat the information you provide to us as confidential information and will not share it. We may, from time to time, send a message on behalf of a relevant partner service where we believe there is legitimate interest.

Because laws applicable to personal information may vary by country, we may put in place additional measures that vary depending on the applicable legal requirements. Information is generally processed and stored in the United States – where the Email on Acid site is being hosted.

We also collect information about the usage of our site and its features, as well as data about our Email Analytics. This data may be used in aggregate form, but never in a way that would identify it with a user of our system. We also collect information about the usage of our site and its features, as well as data about our Email Analytics. This data may be used in aggregate form, i.e. site usage statistics may be used to help us improve our site.

#####  **Email Analytics Data**

If you make use of our Advanced Email Analytics tool, we’ll collect data on the recipients of your email campaigns. This data may include the email addresses of recipients, if you choose to use merge tag tracking. Email on Acid makes every effort to keep this data secure. This data is owned by you. To collect and display this data for you, you allow us access to it. You also allow us use of this data to aggregate (in a non-personally identifiable form) so that we can publish reports and improve our site.

#####  **General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)**

The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is a new European Union (EU) regulation governing the privacy and security of personal data. The regulation gives users more control over how their data is used and imposes heavy fines for companies who fail to comply or suffer data breaches. This regulation took effect May 25, 2018.

Email on Acid takes every step to keep your data safe including encryption and ensuring our third-party partners are GDPR compliant. As data processors, we are committed to addressing privacy throughout the development of new products, processes or services, particularly those that involve using and processing personal data.

Email on Acid complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. Email on Acid has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

Email on Acid is responsible and liable for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Email on Acid complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, UK, and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Email on Acid commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. European Union and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Email on Acid through emailing [helpdesk@emailonacid.com](mailto:helpdesk@emailonacid.com)

Email on Acid has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to JAMS, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not resolved your complaint, please contact or visit JAMS for more information or to file a complaint. The services of JAMS are provided at no cost to you. <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield>

As further explained in the Privacy Shield Principles, a binding arbitration option will also be made available to you in order to address residual complaints not resolved by any other means. For more information, please reference <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>

The Federal Trade Commission has jurisdiction over Email on Acid’s compliance with the Privacy Shield. In certain circumstances, Email on Acid may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities.

#####  **Consent**

Email on Acid collects, tracks and manages users’ consent in compliance with GDPR regulations. We require explicit consent on all forms where we collect personal information; users will see consent checkboxes with details on how we plan to process and use your personal information, particularly on email messages and marketing communications. Users have the right to opt-out of communications at any time.

#####  **Data deletion**

Under GDPR, users have the right to request that Email on Acid permanently deletes any personal data that we may have stored about you, including email tracking history, call records, form submissions, and chat records.  
To request deletion of data, please contact our customer success team: [helpdesk@emailonacid.com](mailto:helpdesk@emailonacid.com).

#####  **Access and Portability of Data**

Under GDPR, users have the right to request access to personally identifiable data (i.e., name, email address). If a user requests access to this data, Email on Acid will provide the user with a copy of the data in either .csv or .xls format. Users also have the right to request to view and verify the accuracy of their data.

California law permits residents of California to request certain details about how their information is shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes. California residents may opt out of having their information shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes.

To request access to personal data, or to request opt out as mentioned above, please contact our support team: [helpdesk@emailonacid.com](mailto:helpdesk@emailonacid.com).

#####  **Modification of Personal Data**

Under GDPR, users have the right to ask Email on Acid to modify personal data if it is inaccurate or incomplete. To request changes to personal data, please contact our support team: [helpdesk@emailonacid.com.](mailto:helpdesk@emailonacid.com)

#####  **Code Repair**

In using our Code Repair service, if we do not have the capacity to manage the request volume, we reserve the right to provide the given email HTML to a third party to help fix an email client rendering issue. The HTML is owned by you and we are only accessing and modifying the code to fix a rendering issue. The HTML or content of that email will not be shared outside of Email on Acid or the third party service provider.

#####  **Account Security**

Because we know that the security of your data is important, we have created a password system to provide account security. It is the user’s responsibility to prevent unauthorized access by protecting their password and access to their computer when using our system.

It is our goal to protect the privacy of your account, but we cannot guarantee complete security. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of user information. Please remember that you control the information that you input, upload or otherwise provide to our services and the data we collect in connection with our Email Analytics.

#####  **Email**

It is our intention to only send you email communications that will be useful to you and that you want to receive. When you create a personal profile on this website, we will occasionally contact you via email and provide information about products and offerings that may be of interest to you. These communications will typically relate to special Email on Acid offers and promotions. If you would prefer not to receive email marketing communications, you may click the “unsubscribe” link in the email.

We use a third-party email service provider to send emails. This service provider is prohibited from using your email address for any other purpose.

#####  **Disclosure of Information to Third Parties**

Email on Acid will never sell your Personal Information to any third party. Email on Acid does employ other companies and people to provide services to our customers within and through the application.

The types of Third-Party Processors we may share elements of your personal data with, for this purpose, include:

  * Payment processors engaged by us to securely store and handle payments information
  * Providers of email management and distribution tools
  * Providers of data aggregation and analytics software services that enable us to effectively monitor and optimize the delivery of our services

#####  **Links to Other Sites**

Email on Acid is only responsible for the privacy statement and content of [www.emailonacid.com](http://www.stage.e360labs.com/). We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the use of cookies on websites that you visit before or after [www.emailonacid.com](http://www.stage.e360labs.com/).

#####  **Email Editor Image Upload Information**

 **How long does Email on Acid store images in the editor?**  
Images will be stored for two years.

 **What does Email on Acid do with data you share with us?**  
We will not modify or alter your media in anyway. We don’t own the copyright to your media; we are simply providing a means of storage.

 **Are images in the image library publicly accessible?**  
By adding your media to our service, you acknowledge that it will be publicly accessible. At this time, we do not offer private hosting.

 **How does Email on Acid handle Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) takedown requests?**  
If there is a takedown request we will be more than happy to comply. We will not contest the request for any reason.

 **What is the uptime guarantee for hosted images?**  
All media is stored in Amazon’s S3 service and we will provide the same 99.9% guaranteed up-time.

#####  **Legal Issues**

This website was developed and is hosted in the United States and is subject to United States law. Email on Acid will disclose personal information without your permission when required by law, or in good faith believe that such action is necessary to investigate or protect against harmful activities toward Email on Acid, its users, or if there has been an infringement of our Terms of Service agreement.

#####  **Privacy Statement Updates**

In the future, we may make updates to this privacy statement. Updates will be completed in this document so that you will always be kept aware of the ways in which we gather and use your personal information.

This privacy statement was last updated on November 26, 2019.
